Guide to the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Records WAG.123
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Neighborhood Service Councils, 1961-1976
  - Housing: G-K, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Housing: L-Q, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Housing: P-S, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Housing: T-Z, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Housing: A-B, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Housing: C, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Housing: D-F, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Housing: G-H, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Housing: I-L, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Housing: M, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Housing: N-Q, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Housing: R, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Housing: S, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Housing: T, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Housing: V-Z, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Income Tax Program, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Income Tax Program, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Inter-Office Memos, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Inter-Office Memos, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Inter-Office Memos, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Invoices, 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Kronberg, Shirley, 1965-1966 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Kronberg, Shirley, 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Legislation, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: A-B, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: C, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: D-E, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: F-G, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: H-I, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: J, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: K-L, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: M, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: N-P, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: R, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: S-U, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - LaUndatedlord-Tenant: V-Z, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Legal Aid, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Legal Aid Society: A-B, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Legal Aid Society: C, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Legal Aid Society: D-F, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Legal Aid Society: G, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Legal Aid Society: H-J, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Legal Aid Society: K-L, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Legal Aid Society: M, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Legal Aid Society: N-Q, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Legal Aid Society: P-R, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Legal Aid Society: S, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Legal Aid Society: T-V, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Legal Aid Society: W-Z, 1971-1974 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Legal Referrals, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Legal Referrals: A-L, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Legal Referrals: M-P, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Legal Referrals: R-W, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Legal Services, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Legislation, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Program, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Legislators, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Legislators: Buffet, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Legislators: Informal Reception, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Local 144: Himes, Ed, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Local 144: Office, 1965-1967 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Lubin, Ruth, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Manhattan, 1961-1967 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Manhattan, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Manhattan, 1970-1976 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Medicaid, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Medicaid: A-B, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Medicaid: C-D, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Medicaid: E-H, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Medicaid: I-L, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Medicaid: M-O, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Medicaid: P-S, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Medicaid: T-Y, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Medical: A, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Medical: B, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Medical: C-D, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Medical: E-G, 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Medical: H-J, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Medical: K-L, 1972-1974 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Medical: M, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Medical: N-R, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Medical: S-U, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Medical: T-Z, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Metropolitan Council on Housing, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Mid-Town Council, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Music aUndated Dance, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - NAACP-CORE, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - National Service Councils: Election CaUndatedidates, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - National Service Councils: Election Nominations, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - O'Hara, James, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Operation Head-start, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Press Association, Inc: Clippings, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Primaries: Registration aUndated November Elections, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Public Housing Applications, 1965-1968 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Queens, Undated (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Registration Literacy Tests, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Rent Control, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Savoy Plaza, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Sloane House, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Social Security aUndated Medicaid Petitions (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Social Services, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Social Services, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Social Services, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Social Services: A-B, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Social Services: C-D, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Social Services: E-G, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Social Services: H-J, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Social Services: K-M, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Social Services: N-Q, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Social Services: R-S, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Social Services: T-Z, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Social Services: A, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Social Services: B, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Social Services: C, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Social Services: D, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Social Services: E, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Social Services: F, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Social Services: G, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Social Services: H, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Social Services: I, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Social Services: J, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Social Services: K, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Social Services: L, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Social Services: M, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Social Services: N, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Social Services: O, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Social Services: P, 1971-1976 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Social Services: Q, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Social Services: R, 1972-1976 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Social Services: S, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Social Services: T, 1972-1976 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Social Services: U-V, 1972-1976 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Social Services: W, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Social Services: Y-Z, 1973-1975 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Social Services-Medical: A, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Social Services-Medical: B, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Social Services-Medical: C, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Social Services-Medical: D, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Social Services-Medical: E, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Social Services-Medical: F, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Social Services-Medical: G, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Social Services-Medical: H, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Social Services-Medical: I-J, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Social Services-Medical: K, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Social Services-Medical: L, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Social Services-Medical: M, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Social Services-Medical: N-O, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Social Services-Medical: P-Q, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Social Services-Medical: R, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Social Services-Medical: S, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Social Services-Medical: T, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Social Services-Medical: V, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Social Services-Medical: W-Z, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Social Services-Medical: A, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Social Services-Medical: B, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Social Services-Medical: C, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Social Services-Medical: D, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Social Services-Medical: E, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Social Services-Medical: F, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Social Services-Medical: G, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Social Services-Medical: H, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Social Services-Medical: I-J, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Social Services-Medical: K, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Social Services-Medical: L, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Social Services-Medical: M, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Social Services-Medical: N, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Social Services-Medical: O, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Social Services-Medical: P-Q, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Social Services-Medical: R, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Social Services-Medical: S, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Social Services-Medical: T, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Social Services-Medical: V, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Social Services-Medical: W, Y, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Spring Dances, 1965-1968 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Staff Report, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - State Legislative Lists, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Statement: J. Algase, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Strecovsky, Vendo, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Summer Program: Trips, 1966-1969 (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Summer Programs, 1963-1967 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Summer Programs, 1968-1972 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - Theater in the Streets, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - Trip: Europe, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - Trip: Hawaii, 1965, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Trip: Montreal Expo, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 40)
  - Trips, 1965-1967 (Box 40, Folder 41)
  - Wage Negotiations: Scholarship, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 42)
- Series VI: Unprocessed Materials, circa 1950-1999
  Series VI: Unprocessed Materials, 1950s-1990s, includes correspondence and other files of Vito Pitta and of HTC staff member Eva Rodriguez; additional hotel files, grievance files, general administrative material and three boxes of videos, photographs and artifacts.
  - Individual Institution Files, A-B, 1976 (Box 41)
  - Individual Institution Files, A-N, 1968 (Box 42)
  - Individual Institution Files, A-H; Tax Forms; Bank Account Summaries, 1969 (Box 43)
  - Individual Institution Files, A-H; Tax Forms; Leases; General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Individual Institution Files, A-C; Tax Forms, 1972 (Box 45)
  - Individual Institution Files, F-Z, 1976-1977 (Box 46)
  - Individual Institution Files, I-Z; Booklet: "Questions and Answers on the Public Employees' Fair Employment Act, 1967.", 1969 (Box 47)
  - Individual Institution Files; P-Z; W(1950), 1950;1975 (Box 48)
  - Individual Institution Files, Misc.; Employees' Contests: "Waiters and Waitress Race" and "Bartenders Mixed Drink Contest.", 1957-1976 (Box 49)
  - Individual Institution Files, K-Z., 1972 (Box 50)
  - Marriott Marquis Hotel Master List, 1986; Membership Lists (Spreadsheets), circa 1980s (Box 51)
  - Compensation Analysis Reports-by Organizational Levels; Lay-Off Lists, 1993-1995 (Box 52)
  - Legal Files: Docket Lists, Negotiations, Grievance Arbitrations, Defensive Litigations, Suspension cases, 1960s-1980s (Box 53)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Impartial Chairman Correspondence; National Committee Meeting, 1987-1993 (Box 54)
  - Hotel Industry Funds; Legal Cases; 1975 Referedum Vote, 1975-1980 (Box 55)
  - Dues; Business Agent Assignments; Local 6 By-Laws, uncertain dates (Box 56)
  - Business Agent Assignments, General Ledgers, G.O. Meetings, 1987; 1988 (Box 57)
  - Incident Files (various years); 1984 Report to COPE Advisory Committee, 1980s (Box 58)
  - Books: Labor Relations Yearbooks, Fair Employment Practice Cases, Labor Relations Refernce Manual, 1960s-1980s (Box 59)
  - Industry Files: Tourism, Labor Department News Releases, Workers' Compensation, Gov. of New York Hugh Carey, 1970s-1980s (Box 60)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Misc. Files; 22nd Constitutional Convention Proceedings and Information., 1982 (Box 61)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Correspondence; Complaints, uncertain dates (Box 62)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Misc. Correspondence, including Stephen Steinbrecher's Letters 1986-1990; Shop Remittance Reports; Arbitration Files 1989, 1980s-1990s (Box 63)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files, circa 1977 (Box 64)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Local 6; Local 153; Collection Statements, uncertain dates (Box 65)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Individual Institution Files (misc.); Union Memos, circa 1995 (Box 66)
  - Vito J. Pitta Files: Newspaper Clippings; Shop Committee Meetings; Personal Files, uncertain dates (Box 67)
  - Grievances, Arbitrations (Local 6, and divided by Institution), circa 1980s (Box 68)
  - Eva Rodriguez Files: Defense Fund Referendum; Dues Referendum; Hacels, Inc. Files (Maintenance Company), Late1980s-1990s (Box 69)
  - Eva Rodriguez Files: NYS AFL/CIO Convention 1992; NYS Council HERE 1993; Financial Statements 1991,1990; Pension Fund; Prescription Drug Program; Investment Committee, circa 1990s (Box 70)
  - Eva Rodriguez Files: Hispanic Labor Committe 1990-1993; HEREIU General Correspondence 1991-1993; Industrial Training Program, circa 1990s (Box 70, Box 71)
  - Eva Rodriguez: Subpoenas; Department of Labor; Vacations 1992-1993; Files on other Unions, 1990s (Box 72)
  - Eva Rodriguez Files: Misc. Correspondence 1993; Local 153, 6, 100; Long Island Federation of Labor, 1990s (Box 73)
  - Douglas Cardu Correspondence; Industry-Wide Collective Bargaining Agreement between Hotel Association of NYC and New York Hotel Trades Council AFL/CIO., 1940-1990 (Box 74)
  - Jay Rubin's Business Agent Files; Labor Books, uncertain dates (Box 75)
  - Jim Donovan Rainbow Organizing Drive, 1995 (Box 76)
  - Individual Institution Files, E-M, 1975 (Box 77)
  - President's Office General Files; Misc. Arbitration Files, uncertain date range (Box 78)
  - Executive Board Minutes; Misc. Receipts, 1970s (Box 79)
  - Hotel Correspondence (by Institution), 1980s-1990s (Box 80)
  - Hotel Correspondence (by institution), 1980s-1990s (Box 81)
  - Hotel correspondence (by institution), 1980s (Box 82)
  - Misc. Subject Files, examples: Buckingham, Baseball, Blue Shield, Con Edison, Hacels, uncertain dates (Box 83)
  - Court Depositions (case files), 1980s (Box 84)
  - 1966 International Convention File; Motel Trades Council 1966/69; Organization Lists and Contributions, 1960s (Box 85)
  - Association of NYC Insurance Fund, including: Pension Fund Actuarial Valuation Review, Union Family Medical Fund of Hotel Industry, 1970s (Box 86)
  - Labor Relations Board Hearings (by institution), 1980s (Box 87)
  - Grievance Files, A-E, F-R (by institution), 1972-1979 (Box 88)
  - Grievance Files, S-W, 1972-1979 (Box 89)
  - Grievance Board Reports (by Series), 1968-1980 (Box 90)
  - Closed Grievances, A-R (by Institution), 1977-1979 (Box 91)
  - Closed Grievances, S-Y (by Institution), 1977-1979 (Box 92)
  - Arbitrations, circa 1977 (Box 93)
  - Softball League Uniform Patches, no date (Box 94)
  - Framed Pictures and Video Tapes, No Dates (Box 95)
  - Video Tapes, 1983-1999 (Box 96, Box 98)
  - Graphics, clippings, photostats, certificates, banner, 1912-1978 (Box 97, Folder 1-8)
- Series VII: Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009-ongoing
  Founded in the 1930s, The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council, AFL-CIO (Hotel Trades Council), is the union of hotel workers in New York City. The Council represents approximately 30,000 non-managerial employees working in all hotel departments, including: housekeeping, public space, dining room, banquet, room service, kitchen, stewarding, bar, mini-bar, audio-visual, front desk, reservations, PBX, bell and door services, concierge, night auditing, laundry, valet, engineering, maintenance, electrical, carpentry, painting, upholstery, business centers, night cleaning, health spas, security, garage, purchasing and receiving, and storeroom in over 300 hotels in the New York City area. It is affiliated with the SEIU, UNITE-HERE, OPEIU, IUOE, IBEW, IUPAT, and USWA. The website includes news listings, a listing of unionized hotels, their weekly newsletter, Hotel Voice, and other multimedia.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Use the following language: Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.